towerdata.com 2017-06-25

# Privacy Policy

The TowerData Privacy Policy is our way of ensuring the safety and accuracy of Internet users' personal information, whether gathered on this site, by our clients, or by our partners.

We are in the data technology business and understand the importance of personal information security. We only work with companies that protect the personal information they collect from their existing or potential customers.  We respect your privacy and are committed to safeguarding it.  This “Privacy Policy” discloses how we gather and use personal information and our compliance with Privacy Shield and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework.

## How We Gather Information

TowerData’s email data technology helps businesses improve their ability to communicate with and understand who their customers are.

When you visit our website, www.towerdata.com, we collect the information you voluntarily give us when you register on our site or complete a “contact us” form. Additionally, like most websites, our servers use log files to list requests made by users to the server.  We use log files to store information such as internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider, visited pages, date and time used and we also gather broad demographic information.

We also receive data through aggregation of personal information received from websites and compilers of websites (data providers) where people have opted-in to receive third party offers through websites or email. The data we receive is maintained in our database and may be shared with clients who use our data enhancement services and with our marketing partners. We mandate that any company that provides us with data for enhancement services certify that the data represents permissible data that they are allowed to share with us and that we are allowed to use. If we become aware that the data is not in compliance, we will terminate our relationship with that company immediately and destroy that data.

## Processor on Behalf

TowerData provides data processing services designed to enable organizations to improve the quality of their customer information. In this capacity, all of the information processed by TowerData is owned and controlled by TowerData's clients. TowerData receives information transferred from the EU and Switzerland to the United States strictly as a processor on behalf of our clients. As a processor on behalf, TowerData acts only on the instructions of its clients and does not control or share such data without direction from the client. For such processing, TowerData enters into appropriate agreements with its clients specifying that the client recognizes that it is a data controller for the purpose of the EU Data Protection Directive and is in compliance with the applicable EU Member State data protection laws or the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection.

## The Use of Cookies

A "cookie" is a small data file transferred by a Web site to your browsing device's hard drive that allows TowerData and/or its partners to identify and match your device with corresponding information in our database. TowerData and our partners send and read cookies when you visit our sites or open our emails, and they are used to track individual responses or views of advertisements or websites. This information may be used to help predict what advertisements may be of interest to consumers and enable the receipt of customized advertisements or content. This may result, for example, in ads for TowerData appearing on websites that you visit. These cookies contain no personally identifiable information. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us or our partners, such as your email address, which we may share with any third party, solely in hashed, non-readable form.  

You can express your choices for display advertising, through the following platforms: Digital Advertising Alliance [opt-out platform](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the Network Advertising Initiative [opt-out platform](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).      

We and/or our partners may also use cookie's for creating personalized advertising emails. These cookies are used to identify the visitors of our advertisers' websites and send personalized emails based on the visitors' browsing experience. For example, if you browse on of our advertisers' websites, you may receive a personalized email promoting the advertiser or the product you were viewing. You will only receive such personalized email if you have consented to receive email from one of our partners (an advertiser, a publisher or an email list provider). To opt out of these emails, [click here](https://dashboard.towerdata.com/optout).

## The Use of Web Beacons

A "web beacon" is programming code used to display an image on a web page and can also transfer an individual’s user identification to a database and associate the individual with previously acquired information about the individual. Web beacons enable TowerData to track certain Web sites you visit or emails or advertisements you view online. Web beacons help determine products or services in which you may be interested and help track online behaviors for marketing purposes.

## How We Use Information

We keep all our customers, and our clients' customers, contact information private and, except as described in this Privacy Policy, never sell, rent or lease this information to others. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we never share the information collected at our websites with any third parties. We only use personal information in a way that is fair and consistent with the reason the recipient supplied us with that information.

TowerData utilizes industry leading data security solutions and has implemented policies and procedures to ensure the physical and electronic security of data stored by TowerData.

We may disclose personal information received directly from you or from our data providers to third party contractors. This disclosure is made for the sole purpose of the third party contractors performing work for TowerData, such as sending our newsletter. These third party contractors are bound by confidentiality restrictions that, amongst other restrictions, only allow use of the information while those contractors are performing services for TowerData. We may also disclose personal information when required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our website.

## You Can Control the Use of Your Information

At any time, you have the right to choose not to receive offers from TowerData . You can do this by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email you received or by contacting us through the methods listed below.

As mentioned above, TowerData maintains a database used for the services we provide to our clients. When asked by clients to validate or enhance data that our clients have, we may access that database. If you do not wish your data to be used as part of that database or if you do not want to receive any future emails from TowerData, you may [opt-out here](https://dashboard.towerdata.com/optout). 

## Access to and Accuracy of Your Information

TowerData strives to keep your personal information secure and accurately recorded. We have implemented technology, management processes, and policies to help maintain data accuracy. TowerData provides individuals with reasonable access to personal information and the reasonable ability to review and correct it or ask for anonymization, blockage, or deletion, as applicable.

To access your data or for questions or comments related to TowerData’s privacy policy, please contact: privacy@towerdata.com or login in to your account here <https://client.towerdata.com/login/> or here [http://intelligence.towerdata.com/ ](https://intelligence.towerdata.com/)

## Privacy Shield

We self-certify compliance with Privacy Shield - <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>

TowerData complies with the [EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework](http://www.privacyshield.gov/) and the [U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. TowerData has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, and Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Resource, Enforcement and Liability. A description of these programs may be found at the following links: [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) and [http://2016.export.gov/safeharbor/swiss/. ](http://2016.export.gov/safeharbor/swiss/)

## Onward Transfer

Any data processed by TowerData will not be further disclosed to third parties except where permitted or required by the processing contract. TowerData complies with the Privacy Shield Principles or the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework for all personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions. Any information TowerData's client (acting as the EU or Swiss controller) identifies as sensitive will be treated accordingly.

## Data Security

TowerData maintains physical, electronic and administrative safeguards to help protect personal data from loss, misuse, or alteration. All information is stored securely and may only be accessed by employees with a legitimate business need to access the information.

## Enforcement

TowerData has a designated individual who is responsible for the internal supervision of TowerData's privacy policies. TowerData educates relevant employees about compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles and has self-assessment procedures in place to ensure its compliance. The DMA serves as TowerData's third-party dispute resolution provider, as required under the Privacy Shield and Safe Harbor Privacy Principles.

If you believe TowerData is not complying with the Privacy Shield or Safe Harbor principles or this policy, contact our company by at:

TowerData, Inc.   
Attn: Privacy Shield  
379 Park Avenue South, 5th Floor  
New York, NY 10016, USA  
Email: [privacyshield@towerdata.com ](mailto:privacyshield@towerdata.com)  
Phone: +1.646.742.1771

If your inquiry with TowerData has not been satisfactorily addressed, you may contact the DMA Privacy Shield/Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Program at:

DMA Privacy Shield  
1333 Broadway, Suite #301  
New York, NY 10018  

<https://thedma.org/resources/consumer-resources/privacyshield-consumers/>

In the event complaints to TowerData and the U. S. Data & Marketing Association do not result in a satisfactory resolution, a consumer may seek binding arbitration. 

TowerData is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. We are required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.

## General 

From time to time, our website may contain links to other sites. TowerData is not responsible for the terms of use or privacy practices and policies of those other sites.  Use of those sites, even if accessed through a link on TowerData’s site, is governed by the other sites own terms and policies. 

TowerData is a business-to-business site and is not directed to children under the age of 13. Similarly, TowerData's services are not directed to nor intended for anyone under the age of 13. Whether for itself or for its clients, TowerData will not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from or about anyone under 13. 

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time for any reason. Use of the information we collect is governed by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information is used or collected. If we make changes in the way we use personal information, we will update this Privacy Policy to reflect that change. Use of the site after the Privacy Policy has been updated confirms agreement with the updated terms.
